# IBRAHIM FIRAT

## ibo.f@hotmail.com

First Class Computer Science graduate with independent learning and problem-solving skills. Equipped with sufficient academic knowledge and ability to adapt in changing & challenging environments. Passionate about technology and related areas. Experience gained from web development, application development, researches and other work experiences. Enjoy developing a broad range of different applications (such as desktop, mobile and web applications) and solving problems.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### 2020-2021

## WEBSITE DEVELOPMENT, MARIBOTECH

Designed and developed blogging website with auth-admin panel using ReactJS, NextJS, Firebase and MERN stack. https://maribotech.com

## 2019 (6 WEEKS)

# **INTERN, KOOPBANK**

Designed and developed queue management system and document upload/download portal for the bank (C# and ASP.NET).

### 2018-2020

# STUDENT AMBADASSOR & STUDENT DEMONSTRATOR, UNI. OF READING

Supporting first year CS students by identifying and solving their programming problems (C and C++). This includes debugging their codes and making suggestions while helping them to finish their assignments. Representing UoR at various events and open days.

#### 2017 (4 WEEKS)

# **INTERN, MULTIMAX (INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDER COMPANY)**

Shadowed a software engineer to learn how to approach and solve problems by dividing them into smaller chunks. Learned how to manage customers when there is a problem.

# **EDUCATION**

**2021 - PRESENT** 

MS COMPUTER ENGINEERING, EASTERN MEDITERRANEAN UNIVERSITY

2017-2020

# **BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE,** UNIVERSITY OF READING (FIRST CLASS BSC DEGREE)

<u>First Year Modules</u>: Applications of Computer Science (68%), Fundamentals of Computer Science (77%), Mathematics for Computer Science (76%), Programming (76%), Software Engineering (56%) and Codes and Code Breaking (86%). **Overall 73.2%**, **First Class Honors**.

<u>Second Year Modules:</u> Algorithms and Operating Systems (90%), Computer Architecture and Networking (67%), Compilers (79%), Databases and Information Security (73%), Human Computer Interactions (65%), Java (82%), Systems Design (76%), Software Quality and Testing (59%). **Overall 75.3%, First Class Honors.** 

<u>Third Year Modules:</u> Service Oriented System Application (72%), Data Science Algorithms and Tools (81%), Image Analysis (71%), Individual Project (64%), Programming in Python for Data Science (96%), Software Engineering: Requirements, Domains and Soft Systems (58%), Social, Legal and Ethical Aspects of Computing (72%), Visual Intelligence (73%), and Visual Reality (75%). **Overall 71.17%, First Class Honors** 

2017-2010

# HIGH SCHOOL, LEVENT COLLEGE

A-Levels ranging from A\* to B, AS-Levels ranging from A to B and IGCSE ranging from A to C.

# TECHNICAL

- **C & C++** -> Projects with C & C++ (including a card-based game and other GUI programs).
- Java and Android -> Developed an intelligent building application (desktop) and a snake game for Android phones.
- C# and .NET -> Developed queue management system and document upload/download portal.
- PL/pgSQL -> Designed and managed databases using PL/pgSQL.
- Python-> Used Python for data science and other daily tasks.
- MERN Stack & NEXTJS -> Currently specializing in MERN & NEXTJS and developing a Blog website.

- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JS and jQuery ->
   Developed a range of different responsive websites.
- Book Chapter -> Wrote a book chapter about botnets "Inevitable battle against botnets" (DOI: 10.4018/978-1-5225-8976-1).
- Penetration Testing: Penetrated into a system and then documented it as a part of information security module.
- Low Level Languages & OS -> Gained experience with low level programming languages. Used different operating systems such as Linux, MacOS and Windows.

# NON-TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Communication and Interpersonal Skills -> In high school, I got elected as student representative of my school. This helped me to develop communication and problem-solving skills as I was negotiating with school administration and helping students to get over their problems.
- Language -> Able to speak English and Turkish fluently.
- Other Experiences -> Selected to participate in Cyprus Friendship Program which aims to maintain peace between the communities of Cyprus. At age of 17, spent a month in USA which helped me to develop independence, initiative and responsibility. Also, giving presentations in front of people helped to express my ideas in a better manner and without any hesitation.

# **ACTIVITIES**

- Travelling -> I enjoy travelling around the world – visited Turkey, United Kingdom, Cyprus, USA, Italy, Spain, Netherlands, Malta, Sweden and Greece.
- **Learning** -> I enjoy learning new languages.
- Sports and Exercise -> In order to stay healthy and keep fit, I go to gym and play table tennis.
- **Socializing** -> I enjoy going out with friends to talk and drink coffee.

Recommendations are available on request.